<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>~kameron</title>
 <link href="http://thelinux.pro/feeds/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://thelinux.pro/"/>
 <updated>2018-05-05T15:16:50-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://thelinux.pro</id>
 <author>
   <name>Ali Polatel</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Shell Meditation</title>
   <link href="http://thelinux.pro/en/blog/2017/01/13/shell-meditation/"/>
   <updated>2017-01-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://thelinux.pro/en/blog/2017/01/13/shell-meditation</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Seek your music. As you please.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;while &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;((&lt;/span&gt; z &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;${&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;RANDOM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; % 100 &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;((&lt;/span&gt; a &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$z&lt;/span&gt; % 10 &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
        mpc seek &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$z&lt;/span&gt;% &amp;amp;
        sleep &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$a&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;kill&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$!&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;wait
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;done&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>First Post</title>
   <link href="http://thelinux.pro/blog/2017/01/03/endgame-tricks/"/>
   <updated>2017-01-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://thelinux.pro/blog/2017/01/03/endgame-tricks</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
Chess endgames often look deceptively simple. Reduced number of pieces on the board
brings reduced alertness to the player. Thus, it is not uncommon for the adversary
to come up with sneaky ways to take advantage of this relaxed state. Thinking in
terms of psychology, the most important feature of this relaxed state is the reduced
feeling of danger which in turn leads to reluctance to justify moves with concrete
variations. Even though, schematic thinking is an important feature of endgame
technique, it has a psychological danger where player's reliance upon natural moves
rather than logical ones can lead h/er to trouble when there exists a non-obvious
nuisance in the position which establishes a significant distinction between the
natural and the logical. At the end of the day chess is purely mathematics and the
term natural is nothing but pattern recognition. Yet, no pattern is exactly the
same.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
One form of blunder which is very common to such a frame of mind is &lt;tt&gt;quiescence
errors&lt;/tt&gt; where the player is decepted by the natural aesthetics of a seemingly winning
move sequence and fails to spot a trap which is no further than half a move away.
The main reason of the blunder is psychological, the sudden change of excitement
coupled with the reduced sense of danger literally blinds the player who could
otherwise easily spot the problem with the move sequence at hand. Below is a simple,
illustrative example of such an error. This is an online blitz game where I had the
white pieces.
&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
